<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<tooltips>
  <library> 
    <Name>The designation of the individual library</Name>
    <Carrier>Specifies the structure in which the peptides are embedded. For example, a phage or viral vector</Carrier>
    <Insert_length>Length of the amino acid sequences that make up the library peptides</Insert_length>
    <Encoding_scheme><![CDATA[The encoding scheme reflects which codons were used to encode the randomized peptides. Examples are:<ul><li>NNN (N= G,A,T or C; All nucleotides possible at all positions in the codon)</li><li>NNK (K = G or T; G or T at the third position in the codon)</li><li>NNS (S = G or C; G or C at the third position in the codon)</li><li>NNB (B = G, C or T; G, C or T at the third position in the codon)</li><li>Trimer (One codon per amino acid possible)</li></ul>]]></Encoding_scheme>
    <Produced_by>Name of the scientist that produced the library</Produced_by>
    <Date>Date of library production</Date>
    <Distinct_peptides>The number of distinct peptide sequences observed in all analyses connected to this library. It will be automatically updated by pepDB, if new sequencing data are. This value does not reflect the total number of peptides in the library, but rather the fraction that has been observed so far.</Distinct_peptides>
    <Peptide_diversity>Peptide Diversity is the estimated number of distinct peptides contained in the library, as determined by PeLiCa (http://www.pelica.org/).</Peptide_diversity>
  </library>
  <selection> 
    <Name>Designation of the selection</Name>
    <Date>Date when the selection was begun</Date>
    <Performed_by>Scientist that performed the selection</Performed_by>
    <Library>Peptide Library used to make the selection</Library>
    <Selection_target>The selection was performed using the following material as target. Specified by species, tissue and/or cells</Selection_target>
    <Species>The species from which the tissue or cells originate, that have been the target of the selection process</Species>
    <Tissue>The tissue that was target of the selection or the tissue from which the cells that have been target of the selection originate from (e.g. “breast cancer” if a selection was performed using a breast cancer cell line).</Tissue>
    <Cell>The cells that have been used as target of the selection. If the selection target was a tissue rather than a specific cell type, this field should remain empty.</Cell>
  </selection>
  <sequencing_dataset>
    <Name>Specific name of the sequencing dataset</Name>
    <Date>Date the sequencing results were received</Date>
    <Peformed_by>Name of the scientist that prepared the samples for sequencing</Peformed_by>
    <Statistics>Link to statistical analyses of the sequences in the sequencing dataset.</Statistics>
    <Library>Library used in the selection</Library>
    <Selection>The selection from which the sequencing dataset was generated</Selection>
    <Overall_reads>Sum over all sequencing reads of every peptide in this sequencing dataset</Overall_reads>
    <Selection_round>Material from this selection round was used for sequencing</Selection_round>
    <Sequencing_target><![CDATA[The sequencing was performed using material from the following target. Specified by species, tissue and/or cells. The <i>sequencing</i> target is not necessarily identical to the <i>selection</i> target.]]></Sequencing_target>
    <Species>The species from which the material originates that has been sequenced.</Species>
    <Tissue>The tissue from which the material originates that has been sequenced.</Tissue>
    <Cell>The cells from which the material originates that has been sequenced.</Cell> 
    <Origin>Form of the genetic material that was used to generate samples for sequencing (e.g. Plasmid, PCR product or Genomic DNA)</Origin>
    <Sequencer>ype of sequencer used to generate the data (e.g. ´standard´ for commercial standard sequencing applications, or specific designations for next generation sequencers).</Sequencer>
    <Read_type>Indicates the technique used for sequencing. ´standard´: normal sequencing; ´single read´: next generation sequencing from one direction; ´paired end´: next generation sequencing from both ends.</Read_type>
    <Read_length>Aproximate length of sequenced DNA. It depends on the used sequencer (e.g. standard sequencer or next generation sequencer) and the used protocol.</Read_length>
    <Used_barcode>If next generation sequencing is used, barcode sequences (e.g. “ATCGATCG”) might be included into the sequenced DNA to associate the results with specific samples.</Used_barcode>
  </sequencing_dataset> 
  <peptide>
    <Peptide_sequence>The amino acid sequence (single-letter code) of the peptide that has been observed in a specific sequencing dataset.</Peptide_sequence>
    <DNA_sequences>The DNA sequence(s) that encode the peptide in the corresponding sequencing dataset.</DNA_sequences>
    <Library>The library from which the peptide originates.</Library>
    <Selection>The selection in which the peptide was observed.</Selection>
    <Sequencing_dataset>The sequencing dataset in which the peptide was observed.</Sequencing_dataset>
    <Rank>The rank reflects the position of the peptide among the peptides of one sequencing dataset. The peptide that was observed in highest abundance has rank 1.</Rank>
    <Reads>The number of sequencing reads that encode the peptide within the sequencing dataset.</Reads>
    <Dominance>The dominance indicates which fraction of all successful reads within a sequencing dataset encodes the peptide. A dominance of “1E+02” would indicate that 100% of all sequencing reads encode the peptide.</Dominance>
    <Peptide_performance>needs description</Peptide_performance>
  </peptide>
  <cluster>
    <Consensus_sequence>The consensus sequence is generated by comparing the peptides in the cluster position by position. Uppercase letters indicate a amino acid that was observed most frequently. Lowercase letters indicate that at the specifc position more than one amino acid with equal frenquencies were observed. The letter shown is one of these observations.</Consensus_sequence>
    <Library>The library the clustered sequenced belong to.</Library>
    <Selection>The selection in which the cluster was observed.</Selection>
    <Sequencing_dataset>he sequencing dataset in which the cluster was observed.</Sequencing_dataset>
    <Dominance_sum>The dominance sum is generated by summating the dominances of all peptides belonging to the cluster.</Dominance_sum>
    <Reads_sum>The reads sum is generated by summating the reads of all individual peptides belonging to the cluster.</Reads_sum>
    <Parameters>This indicates the program and settings used in the clustering process.</Parameters>
  </cluster>
  <comparative-results>
    <Peptide>tba</Peptide>
    <Dataset_inv>tba</Dataset_inv>
    <Dominance>tba</Dominance>
    <General_specifity>tba</General_specifity>
    <Dataset_ref>tba</Dataset_ref>
    <Specifity_score>tba</Specifity_score>
  </comparative-results>
  <peptide-search>
    <Systemic-search><![CDATA[The systemic search allows you to search the database for specific peptides by selecting Library-> Selection -> Sequencing dataset.]]></Systemic-search>
    <Property-search><![CDATA[There are four possibilities to search for peptides by their sequence properties. It is recommended to restrict the search to relevant libraries/selections/sequencing datasets and/or to the selection or sequencing target (as defined by species/tissue/cells). Further it is possible to exclusively search among peptides that meet a minimum prominence (can be defined by maximal rank, minimal number of reads or minimal dominance). 
complete sequence: In this option the complete amino acid sequence of the peptide is entered in single-letter code. Only peptides that fit perfectly to the sequence give a positive result. It is further possible to search for sequences that show a similarity to the given sequence. To do so, enter the number of similar sequences (similar neighbour sequences sollten wir umtaufen in “number of similar sequences”) that should be displayed as well as the minimum similarity quotient. Only peptides that meet the similarity criteria are displayed, even if their number is small as defined under number of similar sequences. The similarity quotient is determined by a comparison of sequence similarity utilizing the Blosum62 matrix (Wenn du hier noch eine bessere Erklärung einbauen kannst ware das super! Das was bisher unter dem “?” zu finden ist verstehe ich allerdings nicht…). The upper extreme value is “1” for an identical peptide. (Ist das korrekt? Kann es negative Werte geben? Können wir hier auch die gesuchten Peptide selber anzeigen? Das wäre sinnvoll.)
partial sequence: In this option a partial stretch of amino acids is entered in single-letter code. pepDB will try to fit the stretch to any position in the peptides that are searched. 
wildcard sequence: In this option the complete sequence is entered, but apart from single-letter amino acids also wildcards can be used. For example “NDVRAV+” indicates all peptides that start with the sequence “NDVRAV” and have a positively charged amino acid in position seven.
reverse wildcard search: In this option the complete amino acid sequence of the peptide is entered in single-letter code. pepDB translates the peptide into the wildcard alphabet used by the wildcard search, and searches for peptides that can be expressed by the combination of wildcard symbols as the query.]]></Property-search>
    <Comparative-peptide-search><![CDATA[The comparative search compares the peptides in one sequencing dataset with those in one or more reference datasets and can be used to determine if a peptide is specific to a certain target tissue. Use of minimum values for peptide dominance is recommended to limit processing time. The results are given as a list and contain individual specificity scores and a general specificity score. The specificity scores compare the dominance of individual peptides within the investigated dataset to the dominance of the same peptide within one reference and ranges from zero to one. A value of “1”, indicates that the peptide is not present in the reference data set. A value of “0.5” indicates that the dominance in the dataset and the reference dataset are identical. A value of “0” indicates that the peptide is only found in the reference dataset. The general specificity score is determined by generating the product of the individual specificity scores and also ranges from zero to one. A high value indicates a high specificity of the peptide for the selected dataset.]]></Comparative-peptide-search>
    <Motif-search><![CDATA[The motif search allows to search in selected sequencing datasets for peptides that match with predefined sequence motifs (select a motif list) that are for example known to interact with certain surface proteins (e.g. integrins) or tissues. The motif lists contain a target (e.g. a tissue) and/or a receptor (a specific structure the peptide motif was shown to interact with) as well as a source (e.g. the PMID code of the publication in which the motif was described). Use of minimum values for peptide dominance is recommended to limit processing time.]]></Motif-search>
  </peptide-search>
  <cluster-search>
    <Peptide-search><![CDATA[With this function peptide sequence clusters can be searched that contain a defined peptide sequence. Additional information on the individual clusters can be obtained by clicking on the cluster. ]]></Peptide-search>
    <Comparative-search><![CDATA[With this function clusters from one sequencing dataset can be compared with those in one or more reference datasets. It can for example be used to determine if certain clusters are specific to a certain target tissue. Also a minimum similarity quotient (range zero to one) has to be defined, that determines if only clusters with identical consensus sequences (similarity quotient = 1) or also clusters with similar consensus sequences are recognized as associated (similarity quotient &lt; 1; required similarity is reduced if the value is lowered). The similarity quotient is determined by a comparison of sequence similarity utilizing the Blosum62 matrix (Wenn du hier noch eine bessere Erklärung einbauen kannst ware das super!). A minimum for the cluster dominance sum can be defined.
The results are given as a list and contain individual specificity scores and a general specificity score. The specificity scores compare the dominance sums of individual clusters within the investigated dataset to the dominance sums of clusters within one reference and ranges from zero to one. A value of “1”, indicates that the cluster is not present in the reference data set. A value of “0.5” indicates that the dominance sum in the dataset and the reference dataset are identical. A value of “0” indicates that the cluster is only found in the reference dataset. The general specificity score is determined by generating the product of the individual specificity scores and also ranges from zero to one. A high value indicates a high specificity of the cluster for the selected dataset. ]]></Comparative-search>
  </cluster-search>
</tooltips>
